[Music]
there we go
welcome back to the channel
apparently my ice cream is upside down
anyway
this video is mostly about this
cheesecake but not just any old
cheesecake this is
a burnt basque cheesecake
how is it different to normal cheesecake
it's more of a cakey kind of cheesecake
i've never made one before but i wanted
to make cheesecake ice cream
actually my wife wanted the cheesecake
ice cream and i love cheesecake so it
kind of made sense just to make one a
little bit different so we thought we'd
have a look online we chose crumbs and
doilies
burnt basque cheesecake
made this
and then did some ice cream stuff as
well so if you want to see how we make
both
stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
so for this burnt bath cheesecake we're
going to start with our cream cheese
we've gone with philadelphia here
straight off the shelf nothing fancy
make sure that's at room temperature put
it in a bowl add in your sugar and get
it really nicely combined and smooth at
that stage and you're going to add all
your eggs one at a time make sure
they're just nicely combined you're not
trying to whip this at all you're just
trying to get those eggs combined well
then add in your flour
get that nicely mixed in and finally
your cream
once that's all completely combined
you're going to take your springform pan
and put in some baking parchment make
sure there's some nice folds around the
edges make sure it goes over the edges
as well because this will rise in the
oven
pour your mix into your pan and then put
it in a preheated oven at 200 c
fan
for 45 to 50 minutes
check on it through the cooking process
to make sure you don't open the door
but our oven is notorious for being too
hot so i actually had to turn ours down
ours is maybe a little bit more burnt
than
ideal but you know ultimately it still
tastes great
once it's finished take it out of the
oven and let it cool down to room
temperature once at room temperature put
it in the fridge overnight minimum
[Music]
now we're going to move on to the ice
cream what we're going to do is make a
lemon cheesecake base so for that you're
gonna start with your milk in your pan
and then add in your sugars here we've
gone we've gone with dextrose and normal
table sugar in our table sugar we've
added our stabilizer you don't have to
do it remember but i like to because i
might not eat it all in one go
once that's all combined you're going to
take your mask pony cheese this is 250
grams this cream cheese was actually
straight out the fridge so you can get
this to room temperature make it easier
for yourself when trying to combine with
the milk but if not just keep whisking
it in your pan and eventually it will
all come together nicely
and then at that stage add in your milk
powder once that's all completely
finished turn off the heat and add in
your lemon extract we've gone with
nelson mason lemon extract here it's
really good quality stuff
give that a final mix and then take it
off the heat completely and put it in a
container the final step as always like
i do with all my ice creams is add in
the cream there's not a lot of cream
going in here because the mascarpone is
super high fat at 40 percent
give it one final little mix and put
that in the fridge to chill down that's
going to take about three to four hours
once your ice cream mix is completely
chilled take it out the fridge give it a
final stir and put it in your machine to
churn now whilst that's churning you can
take your burnt basque cheesecake out
the fridge
and try not to eat it like i'm doing
here but you what you really want to do
is kind of just cut it up into usable
cubes as you can see we've got a plate
full of these cheesecake cubes ready
here gonna keep them in the fridge until
the ice cream is completely churned
and finally when your ice cream is
churned start loading up your tub a
scoop at a time and add in some cubes of
your cheesecake as you go completely
fill the tub using this method and then
just top with two or three cubes of your
burnt bass cheesecake to finish off put
that in the freezer to harden for four
or five hours
[Music]
there we go the ice cream is out the
freezer i've got the cheesecake to hand
i mean it's just for visual i'm not
going to eat all of this i mean the
calories and this litre of ice cream and
this cheesecake alone
i tried to think it's probably something
around four to five thousand
calories just in these two items
i'd probably give it a go though i think
i'd have to fast for a day or two but
look at that
probably overexposed
but let's get some scoot up in a bowl
and see what this tastes like
there we go scooped so we've got a lemon
cheesecake ice cream with a burnt basket
cheesecake
chunks scattered throughout
it's the first time we've ever used
lemon extract it's really good it's got
a nice strong flavor i don't know how it
tastes so
let's just try some of the ice cream
first
it's it's really nice flavor
very natural kind of lemon flavor that
you get from the lemon oils
from the rind i i'll normally just use
lemon rind
you know one or two per
one or two lemons depending on the size
per liter of ice cream base is normally
more than enough to get a nice strong
flavor
some people
say that their lemon ice cream is a bit
weak in flavor and i think that's to do
with the type of lemons and the size of
lemons more than anything else so just
check you know if you're looking at
something that's small
then you know you might need to use two
or three but if you've got huge great
lemons
or milky lemons or something like that
then you know one or one and a half
might suffice but let's try some of this
cheesecake that's in here as well
the cheesecake chunks are really really
good
they've frozen but they're not frozen
completely solid so just like um
it's like a slight chewiness to it
which is really nice when you dig in
the mascarpone flavor comes through in
the ice cream just a little bit
it's not overwhelmingly so
it's just nice that
the ice cream actually has a flavor
profile more in line with new york
cheesecake
and to have the chunks of this
basket cheesecake through it it's a
really nice kind of
change of texture and taste
it's very refreshing ice cream
and
although
the top of our
basque cheesecake is definitely
or does harbor the burnt element of the
name's sake
it kind of works in this because
it's very sweet lemon ice cream can be
very very sweet
and to have that
kind of caramelization or super
caramelization really cuts through that
sweetness really nicely
really gives you three different flavors
you get the mascarpone the lemon and
then you get that caramelization come
through from the outside of the
cheesecake
overall this is excellent this is really
really nice combo
super creamy and smooth
really really nice texture
flavor is excellent the texture of that
cheesecake you know what i i reckon that
cheesecake might just be better in the
freezer on its own rather than in the
fridge but that's personal preference
anyway i'm going to start digging
through the rest of this
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next time
you